Guitar strings sure are scary.
ギターの弦って 怖いよね
They're thin and tough, and I'm scared I'll cut my fingers.
細くて硬いから 指切っちゃいそう
You got that right! If you're not careful, you'll slice your fingers to the bone, and blood will spurt out everywhere!
そうだぜ
気をつけないと
指がスパーッと切れて
血がドバーッと…
キャーッ！
Mio, why did you scream?
澪ちゃんが悲鳴を…
I-I can't stand all that gory talk!
いッ 痛い話はダメなんだ
Don't worry Mio, I'm fine.
大丈夫だよ
See? I'm not really bleeding. I'm perfectly okay.
ほら ホントに血が出てるわけじゃないから
Your fingertips will toughen up the more you play and practice,
まあ 練習しているうちに 指の先が硬くなるから
so I can almost promise you that you won't be doing any bleeding.
血が出たりすることは ないよ
ほら
Here, check it out!
Wow, Mio, you're right! They're all squishy!
本当だ
ぷにぷに～
Squishy, squishy, squishy...
Squishy, squishy...
ぷにぷに～
Um, are you about done?
あの… もういいかな？
No, let me squeeze them some more!
もッ もうちょっとだけ
TRIPPIN' OUT
Chatting Now
ガチでカシマシ　Never Ending Girls' Talk
It's really noisy
Never ending girls talk
I can't wait until the bell
rings at the end of class
終業チャイムまで待てない
Even if I'm late,
leaving early is a
遅刻はしても早退はNon Non Non!
No no!
精一杯Study After School
study
hard
I'll
after
School
ドキドキが止まんない　フルスロットルな脳内
My heart won't stop thumping
Why is it going on full throttle?
希望·欲望·煩悩　リボンかけて包装
Hope
Desire
Suffering
Wrap them all up with a ribbon
ネタどっさり持ち寄り　New　Type　Version打ち込み
I'll gather lots of data
and I'll put it all in a new type
男子禁制のプリ帳　恋綴った日記帳
I have a photo album without guys
and a diary written with love
スカート丈2cm　詰めたら跳ぶよ
If I cut my skirt
by 2 centimeters,
I can fly
昨日より遠く　おとといよりオクターブ高く
Further than yesterday,
I'll reach a higher octave
than the day before
Jumping
out
Jumping Now
ガチでウルワシ　Never Ending Girls' Life
It's beautiful
Never ending
girls life
日々マジ　ライブだし待ったなし
I'm looking
forward
to the daily
concert
早起きしても早寝はNon Non Non!
Even if I
get up early,
going to bed
early is a
No no!
Fight with all
目一杯Shouting　わっしょい
W
e've
got
Hooray
It's splendid
ガチでスバラシ　Never Ending Girls' Song
Never ending
Girls talk
午後ティータイムには持ってこい
The afternoon
tea  time
is perfect
My unrequited
L
O
V
E
will be defeated
片思いでも玉砕でHere we go!
But here I go!
歌えばShining After School
I'll
sing
for
you
After school
I know I'm supposed to practice, but I have absolutely no idea where I should even start.
ギターを練習するっていっても
一体 何から始めていいやら わかんないや
Here.
はい
Huh?
You should probably start yourself off by learning all of the chords.
とりあえず最初は コードを覚えるといいよ
Wow, thank you!
ありがとう
Um, could you please teach me how to read musical notation first?
まッ まずは楽譜の読み方から教えてください
You don't even know that?!
そこから!?
Special Training!
See you!
バイバーイ
Bye bye!
See you tomorrow!
じゃ また明日
Let's see...
えーっと
A "C" goes like this, and this is a "D"...
Ｃがこうで Ｂがこう
Yui!
唯
あッ 和ちゃん
Nodoka!
What's that? A new kind of greeting?
何それ 新しいあいさつ？
The thing is, I had them teach me a bunch of guitar chords today!
実はね 今日 ギターのコードを教えてもらったんだ
へえ～ 頑張ってるのね
Sounds like you're really working hard.
Speaking of which, you're heading home a lot later than usual today.
そういや 和ちゃん 今日 帰るの遅いんだね
Mm, I spent the afternoon in the library studying for our midterms.
うん 図書館で中間テストの勉強してたから
へえ～
Ah! We've got midterm exams?!
中間テスト!?
Is that a chord too?
それも コード？
Oh, wow... It's time for midterms already?
そっか～ もう中間テストなのか
And here I was all set to buckle down and really practice my guitar...
せっかく頑張って ギター練習しようと思ったのに
Oh, come on now, Yui. It's not like you've studied for a single test since middle school.
あんた 中学のときから
試験勉強なんて したことなかったじゃない
Oh, yeah, that's right!
そっか なら大丈夫だね
Well, I guess it's all good, then!
Um, I wouldn't exactly say that...
いや 大丈夫じゃないけど…
Sign: Preparation Room
We're finally free of all those tests!
やっとテストから解放された
It's terrible, the way they suddenly got harder once we got into high school.
高校になって 急に難しくなって 大変だったわ
That's for sure.
そうだな
And I... see someone who's having an even harder time than we did.
そして もっと大変そうなやつが ここに…
Did your tests go that badly, Yui?
そんなにテスト 悪かったのか？
Seems I'm the only one in my class who has to take a make-up...
クラスで ただ１人 追試だそうです
E-Everything will be fine!
だッ 大丈夫よ
I'm sure it's just that you didn't really study properly this time.
今回は 勉強の仕方が悪かっただけじゃない？
Mugi's right! Just study real hard, and you'll ace that make-up test easy!
そうそう ちょっと頑張れば
追試なんて余裕 余裕
Actually, I didn't study for it at all.
勉強は まったくしてなかったけど
励ましの言葉 返せ コノヤロー！
I take back my words of encouragement, you flake!
I don't get it, Yui. Why didn't you study?
何で勉強しなかったのさ
Oh, I really had planned to, but I... come on, when you study for a test, don't you ever end up fixating on everything but studying?
いや～ しようと思ったんだけれど
なんか 試験勉強中ってさ
勉強以外のことに 集中できたりしない？
Ah, I know what that's like. Like when I gotta clean up my room and stuff.
それはあるな 部屋の掃除 はかどったりな
I practiced on the guitar when I was taking a break from studying, and I couldn't put it down.
勉強の息抜きに ギターの練習したら
抜け出せなくなっちゃって
In the end, I didn't get any studying done at all.
結局 全然勉強できなかったの
But...
でもね
my time wasn't wasted, 'cause I learned a whole bunch of chords!
おかげで コードいっぱい弾けるようになったよ
How about applying those powers of concentration to your studying, huh?
その集中力を少しでも勉強に回せば…
You're a big talker. How did you do, Ritsu?
そういう りっちゃんはどうだったのさ
Huh? Who, me?
あッ 私？
Passed with flying colors, thank you very much!
余裕ですよ このとおり！
You know, this doesn't really fit with your character...
こんなの りっちゃんのキャラじゃないよ
When you're a brilliant renaissance girl like me, everything comes quite easily to you!
私ぐらいの人間になると
何でもそつなくこなしちゃうのよ
Yeah, but I was always under the impression that you were just like me!
りっちゃんは 私の仲間だって 信じてたのに
Who was it that showed up on my doorstep in tears the night before the exam?
テストの前日に泣きついてきたのは どこの誰だっけ？
Hey, she doesn't need to know that!
バラすなよ
Now that's the Ritsu I know.
それでこそ りっちゃんだよ
I don't wanna hear that from somebody who flunked the test!
赤点取ったやつに 言われたくねえ！
How about the two of you? How did you do on your tests?
澪ちゃんとムギちゃんは 何点だったの？
Here.
はい
Oh, well, you know, how it goes sometimes. I just made a bunch of dumb mistakes. That's all!
まッ まあ そんなもんだよな
私 ポカミスしちゃったからさ
Have a heart, please say something!
頼むから 何か言ってくれ
On another day...
別の日
Thank you for your time.
失礼しました
Oh, look at that! It's sweet bean jelly!
今日は ようかん～
They said I'm banned from all club activities until I pass the make-up exam.
追試の人は 合格点取るまで部活動禁止だって
Wow, Yui, that's pretty harsh...
結構 厳しいな
Well, then, is it okay for you to even be here?
そしたら ここにいるのもマズイんじゃ…
Oh, sure, it's okay. I'm just here to eat sweets with my good friends.
大丈夫だよ
お菓子 食べに来てるだけだし
Oh, right. Then everything is fine!
そっか それなら安心だ
How do you say that it's okay?!
…って 何でやねん！
もしも唯が部活できなくなったら
If you're banned from participating in clubs, that means our club will be back down to three members.
私達 ３人だけになっちゃうんだよ
No way, are you saying that we'll--
てことは ひょっとして…
We won't meet the minimum requirement.
部員数が足りなくなる
We'll be... disbanded?
それで 廃部？
When is your make-up test?
追試は いつあるの？
One week from today.
１週間後
A week from today, huh?
１週間後か…
Well, with that much time, it's okay for me to come here every day, right?
そんだけあれば
毎日 ここに来ても大丈夫だよね
そんだけしかないのッ
That's not much time at all!
Yui, if you don't pass your test next week, the Light Music Club might very well cease to exist.
追試に受からないと
このクラブ自体もなくなるかもしれないんだよ
Yeah, you're right.
そうだよね みんなと部活続けたいから
I wanna keep doing fun stuff with you guys, so I'll work real hard!
私 頑張る
Okay, time to study. Let's do this!
さてと…やるぞーッ！
How did I let this get so messy?
何で こう 散らかってるかなあ
あッ
わッ もう こんな時間！
Wow, it's that late?
I have to bathe and get to bed!
お風呂入って 寝なきゃ
Sign: 6 days until the make-up
Meetings sure aren't as worthwhile without Yui here.
なんか 唯がいないと 張り合いがないな
That hasn't seemed to affect your appetite.
そのわりには よく食ってるな
I know, Mio, those two things have absolutely nothing to do with each other!
それとこれとは話が違いますわん～
I wonder if Yui's devoting herself to her studying?
唯 ちゃんと勉強してるかな
Oh, I'm sure she's doing fine.
大丈夫なんじゃない？
For x² - y², it's subtract y² divided by x. So, x = y² / x
x² : x squared
/ : divided by
= : equals
えっと… ｘ二乗マイナスｙ二乗 イコール
カッコ ｘマイナスｙ カッコ閉じ…
See, I can do this if I set my mind to it!
私ってば やればできるんじゃない？
This is x²y - 4y, so I start by factoring out the y, leaving me with (x² - 4).
( ) : the sum of
ｘ二乗ｙマイナス４ｙは
最初ｙで くくって
カッコ ｘ二乗マイナス４ カッコ閉じ…
Sign: 3 days until the make-up
Yui's studying has to be coming along well, right?
唯 勉強 進んでるはずだよね
You know, I've been wondering that, too.
進んでるかなあ
All right, now I'm really getting worried, guys!
やっぱ 心配になってきた
Hey, I know, why don't we all send her an encouraging text tonight?
今晩 みんなで励ましのメールしてあげるのは どう？
おお 名案だな
Good idea!
I'm gonna send her as soon as I get home!
うん 私もやってみるよ
Oh, hey, it's from Mio.
澪ちゃんからだ
Mio-chan / (no title) / Have you been studying properly? Unpreparedness is your greatest enemy.
Message received.
了解です
It's from Mugi-chan!
ムギちゃんだ
Sorry for bothering you so late at night. Do your best, but don't overexert yourself.
I have tasty snacks waiting for you.
Thank you so much, Mugi-chan.
ありがとう ムギちゃん
It's from Ritchan!
りっちゃん
Take my yell!
Sign: 2 days until the make-up
No matter how harder I try, I just don't have the focus that I need.
私って やっぱり集中力が足りないんだよね
Book: Even a monkey can do it!!
5 Minute Concentration Training
But with this, I'm gonna be just fine!
でも これさえあれば もう大丈夫
All right, I'll use this book to boost my concentration for the first five minutes.
とりあえず 最初の５分は これで集中力をつけて…
It's no use! I just can't read this!
ダメだ この本も読んでられない
No, no, no, no!
ダメ ダメ ダメ
The problem is that I always give up before I even start!
ここで あきらめるから ダメなんだよね
And that's why I need you to help me, Mio!
Top: Preparation Room
Bottom: The day before the make-up
というわけで 澪ちゃん 助けて！
You mean that you didn't do any studying at all?
えッ？勉強してきたんじゃないの？
I just couldn't do it!
できなかった
But if you don't get a passing grade, we'll--
合格点 取れなかったら 私達…
That's the last thing I want to have happen!
それだけは絶対したくないッ
う～ん
We'll have to have a cram session tonight.
よしッ 今晩 特訓だ
You mean it?
本当？
Listen, if you have Mio teaching you, you're gonna pass your exams for sure!
澪に教えてもらえば 確実に合格点取れるぞ
She's really great at cramming information into your head!
うまいんだぜ 一夜漬け教えるの
I'm gonna teach her normally, darn it!
うおーい 普通に教えるよッ
けいおん！
My dad had to go away on a business trip, and my mom decided to go with him, so we don't have to worry about disturbing anyone.
今日は お父さんが出張でね
お母さんも付き添いで いないから
気兼ねしなくていいよ
Hey, didn't you say that you also had a little sister?
あれ？妹がいるって言ってなかった？
Mm, yeah, and I'm pretty sure she'll be at home tonight.
うん 妹は帰ってきてると思う
Well, if she's home, won't we just be a bother to her?
それだと お邪魔にならないかしら？
Yui's little sister, huh?
唯の妹か…
Big Sister!
お姉ちゃーん
Little Sister!
妹～
Big Sister!
お姉ちゃーん
I think we'll be pretty safe on that score!
ぜーんぜん 大丈夫なんじゃない？
Come in, everyone.
みんな 上がって 上がって
Thanks having us over.
お邪魔しまーす
Hi, welcome home, Sis.
お姉ちゃん おかえり
Oh, are these your friends?
あれ お友達？
はじめまして 妹の憂です
It's a pleasure to meet you.
I'm Yui's sister, Ui.
Thank you for looking out for my sister.
姉がお世話になってまーす
Here are some slippers for you.
スリッパを どうぞ
So polite and mature!
できた子だ～
Sign: Yui's Room
Hard to believe two sisters could be so different.
姉妹で こうも違うもんかね
Different how?
何が？
It's almost like your little sister managed to get all the good traits in the family.
妹さんに 唯のいいところ
全部 吸い取られたんじゃないの？
What?!
ひど～い！
Excuse me. I brought some tea if anyone would like some.
あの～皆さん よかったらお茶どうぞ
And sorry, I'm afraid these are the only snacks we have for you.
買い置きのお菓子で 申し訳ないんですけど
She really is polite and mature!
本当に できた子だ！
憂ちゃんは 今 何年生？
So, what grade are you in, Ui?
I'm in ninth grade.
中３です
Just one year behind us!
１つ違いじゃん
Taking your entrance exams?
受験生ですね
Just about.
はい
Do you know which high school you wanna go to?
どこ受けるか もう決めてる？
I'd like to go to Sakuragaoka if I can manage it.
できれば 桜が丘に行きたいんですけど
But I'm not sure if I'm a good enough student to get in.
私の学力で 受かるかどうか…
You sister managed to get in, so I'm sure you'll do fine.
お姉ちゃんでも受かったんだから
大丈夫だよ
Join us, join us!
おいで おいで～ッ
You just gotta get your sister to help you study, that's all.
お姉ちゃんに 勉強 教えてもらえばいいんじゃない？
Yup!
I, uh... I'd rather do it all by myself.
それは…
自分で できるから
Boy, she shot you down!
断られたぞ～
ええッ 何で 何で～？
Why? I can study just as good as anybody!
But you know, my sister can do anything once she sets her mind to it.
でッ でも お姉ちゃんは やるときには やる人です
やっぱり できた子だ～
Definitely polite and mature.
All right, we don't have a lot of time, so this is gonna be concentrated.
じゃあ あんまり時間ないから 集中していくよ
うん
Page 20 in the book.
教科書 20ページ
This expression.
じゃあ この式
うん
What do you get when you expand it using this one?
これ 展開してみると どうなる？
グルグルグル グル～
Here.
ここ
Oh, I get it.
漫画
Oh, manga!
ああ そっか
Would you shut up!
ああ もう！
Yeah, my feet are asleep again.
足が しびれた
Poke.
ちょびん
Ritsu!
律！
It's no use, I just can't concentrate anymore!
ダメだー 集中力が続かない
Come on, now, Yui. It's only been 30 minutes since we started working.
おいおい 始めて まだ30分しかたってないぞ
Yui, when you're done studying, we can all eat this cake that I brought,
唯ちゃん ケーキ持ってきたから あとで食べよう
so hang in there a while longer, okay?
だから もう少し頑張って
Attagirl, Mugi!
さすが ムギ
How can I get back in there?
どうやって中に入ったものか
Oh, hello, girls! I see y'all hard at work.
おう みんな やっとるかね
Well, that didn't work.
ダメだったか
Yay! It's me, everybody!
イエーイ 私だよん！
I needed an entrance with more impact.
やはり ここはインパクトか
That's it xxx all present! I am cop...!
たのもう！
Shut up!
やかましい！
This is so great!
おいしい～
Cake like this makes life worth living.
このために生きてるって感じ
Boy, what kind of life do you two lead, anyway?
この子達の人生って 一体…
Coming!
はい
I wonder who that is?
誰かな？
Oh, hi Nodoka.
あッ 和ちゃん
So, are you making any progress?
どう はかどってる？
I am. Thanks for asking.
うん おかげさまで
Your friends from the Light Music Club?
皆さんが 軽音楽部の？
Let me introduce you.
紹介するね
This is Mio Akiyama.
こちら 秋山澪ちゃん
And Ritsu Tainaka.
で 田井中律ちゃんに
And this is Tsumugi Kotobuki.
琴吹紬ちゃん
Nice to meet you.
よろしく～
Nice to meet you, too.
真鍋和です 唯とは家が近所で
My name is Nodoka Manabe. Yui and I have been friends forever.
幼なじみなんだけど
We even ended up in the same class in high school.
高校でも同じクラスになりました
Yeah, we've been together pretty much since kindergarten.
幼稚園から ほとんど一緒なんだよ
We have this weird connection.
不思議な縁よね
Anyway, I thought you all might get hungry so I brought you some sandwiches.
それより ほら サンドイッチ作ってきたわよ
おおッ ちょうどおなか 減ってたとこ
Great timing, I was just getting hungry!
Didn't you just finish eating cake?
今 ケーキ 食べてたじゃん
No problem at all! Just pass them over here!
全然 オッケー 出して出して
Thank you!
ごっつあんです
In middle school, I came down with a bad fever and had to miss classes for a while.
中学のとき 私が熱を出して しばらく休んでたんだけど
毎日 唯が プリントを持ってきてくれたんだよね
Yui came over every day to bring me that day's syllabus and homework.
I've actually never been sick a day in my life!
私 カゼひいたことなくて
One day, she accidentally left one of her test papers in the daily syllabus that she brought over.
でもね その持ってきてくれたプリントの中に
唯のテストも間違って入ってて
You haven't changed one bit!
変わってないな～
But she really was a huge help to me.
でも 本当に助かったんだよ
Reminds me of that time, Ritsu--
それだったら 律も…
言うなよ
No, don't tell them out!
She what? Tell us!
なになに？
You're not gonna believe this, but Ritsu actually--
実はね 律ったらさ…
That can't be true!
ありえねえ
You did it!
それは ないよね
By the way, are you done studying?
ところで 勉強 大丈夫なの？
All right, everything we've covered so far will be on the test.
いい？ここまでが試験範囲だからね
In the case of the occasion x² - xy - 6y² + 2x - y + 1,
ｘ二乗マイナスｘｙマイナス ６ｙ二乗プラス
２ｘマイナスｙプラス１は
you wanna first simplify by trying to factor out the common factor of x.
まず こう ｘの共通因数でくくってみると…
Now when we do that, what we end up with is x² - (y - 2)...
こうなって
ｘ二乗マイナス カッコ ｙマイナス２ カッコ閉じ
and x - 6y² - y + 1
ｘマイナス６ｙ二乗 マイナスｙプラス１
= x² - (y - 2) times (2y + 1)...
イコール ｘ二乗マイナス
カッコｙマイナス２ カッコ閉じ
ｘマイナス…
Wake up!
起きろ～ッ！起きてくださーい！
Please, get up!
Huh? Where am I?
ここは？
Yui, stay awake! You'll die if you doze off!
唯 寝るな 寝たら死ぬぞ！
I came this close to falling asleep!
危うく寝ちゃうところだった
Wait a minute.
あれ 隊長 りっちゃん隊員がいません
Commander, I don't see Squad Member Ritsu here!
She's outside, and she's... playing!
あんなところで遊んでます
It pains me to say it, but there is absolutely nothing I can do for her.
残念だが 私の力ではどうすることもできない
No!
はッ はい！
Hey, Yui?
ちょっと 唯
もう～
Oh, Squad Member Ritsu!
りっちゃん隊員
May fortune... smile upon you!
ごぶッ ご武運を…
(x - 2y + 4)
カッコ ｘマイナス２ｙプラス４ カッコ閉じ
カッコ ｘマイナスｙマイナス１ と…
(x - y - 1)...
Yes, I'm all done!
できた！
Well, I think you've got the hang of it now.
これだけ解けたら 大丈夫だろう
You'll be able to ace the make-up test.
これで追試もバッチリね
Thanks, Mio-chan, and Thanks you, Mugi-chan!
ありがとう 澪ちゃん ムギちゃん
I think it's time we called it a night.
それじゃあ 私達はそろそろ…
Hey, where's Ritsu?
あれ 律は？
ああ～ また負けた
Oh, I lost again!
She's getting way too cozy.
Wait! Lost again?
なじみすぎ
っていうか「また」って…
Very well, begin!
では はじめ
I wonder how Yui is doing?
唯 大丈夫かな？
Oh, I think she's gonna be just fine.
大丈夫なんじゃないの～？
Isn't that thing you should worry for?!
もっと 心配しろ！
あッ 平沢さん
Ah, Miss Hirasawa.
Ms. Yamanaka.
先生…
So, how did your test go?
どうだった？ 追試
It went...
はいー
It certainly looks like you studied hard for it.
頑張って勉強したみたいね
なッ 何ごとも あきらめなければ
As long as you don't give up, you're sure to succeed eventually!
結果は ついてくるものよ
Yui gets her results today, right?
Top: Preparation Room
Bottom: A Few Days Later
今日返却だよね
I wonder if she was able to pass this time?
合格点 取れてるかな 唯
After all the studying, I'm sure she did fine.
あれだけ勉強したから 大丈夫のはず
Well, how did you do?
どッ どうだった？
What am I gonna do, Mio?
どうしよう 澪ちゃん
えッ また ダメだった？
You mean you failed again?!
I got a hundred!
100点 取っちゃった
You got a what?!
極端な子！
Thank goodness. Now all of your tests are behind you for the time being.
でも よかった
とりあえずこれで ひと段落だな
Yeah, she's right.
そうだね
I couldn't have done it without you guys! Thank you so much!
みんなのおかげだよ
本当にありがとう
Oh, well, it was nothing!
いや～ それほどでも
You didn't do a damn thing to help!
お前は何もしていないッ
Let's get right down to practicing, then, shall we?
じゃあ 早速練習しましょう
Now, you were practicing your chords while you were studying, weren't you?
試験勉強中にも コードの練習をしたってことだし
Why don't you try playing something.
ちょっと弾いてみてよ
I have it down cold! Ask me anything! X, Y, whatever!
バッチリだから ｘでもｙでも 何でもごじゃれ
All right, then. Why don't you play us a C chord followed by an A minor 7, a D minor 7, and then a G7.
じゃあＣ エーマイナーセブン ディーマイナーセブン
ジーセブンって弾いてみて
Sure thing!
ほいほい
What's the matter?
どうしたの？
I forgot how...
忘れた
It's all of the X and Y stuff I've been studying.
ずっと ｘとかｙとか 勉強してたから
So you're back to square one?!
また１から!?
Um, let me see. Was this an X?
ええと これがｘだっけ？
Wait, I've never seen that chord before.
ちょッ そんなコード見たことないぞ
Oh, it's brand-new. See, it's like this!
違う こうだ こうだ
Mio, I'm positive this is an X!
澪ちゃん これがｘだよ
But there's no such thing as an X chord!
だから そんなのないってば
You can play that?
それは弾けるんかい！
Please
don't say
you are
lazy,
Please don't say“You are lazy”
because
you are
actually
crazy
だって本当はcrazy
The swans
are actually
白鳥たちはそう　見えないとこでバタ足するんです
kicking their legs
hard out
of sight
Being true and sincere to my instincts,
I accept that I'll
be tossed around
本能に従順 忠実　翻弄も重々承知
The path ahead looks bright
前途洋々だし…だからたまに休憩しちゃうんです
That's why I
take rests
sometimes
近道あればそれが王道　はしょれる翼もあれば上等
If there's a shortcut,
it's the best route
If I have wings to use, then it'll be the best
ヤバ 爪割れた　グルーで補修した
Crap, I broke a nail!
I'll fix it with glue
That's enough to give me
a sense of achievement
それだけでなんか達成感
大事なのは自分　かわいがること
What's important is to take good care of yourself
自分を愛さなきゃ　他人も愛せない
If you can't love yourself, then you can't love someone else
Please
don't
say
you
are
Please don't say“You are lazy”
because
you
are
actually
だって本当はcrazy
Skilled
hawks
能ある鷹はそう　見えないとこにピック隠すんです
hide their talons
out of sight
I try to use my imagination,
想像に一生懸命　現実は絶体絶命
but reality is a bitch
I'm still just learning,
発展途中だし…だから不意にピッチ外れるんです
so I'll be out of pitch sometimes
Next Episode
We're having a training camp!
合宿をします！
合宿？
Training camp?
そう もうすぐ夏休みだし
That's right. For one thing summer vacation is almost here.
We're going to the beach?! Or maybe to the mountains?!
もしかして 海？
それとも 山とか？
We're not going out there to play around!
遊びに行くんじゃありません
バンドの強化合宿
This will be a band training camp!
We'll be practicing nonstop from sunup to sundown.
朝から晩まで みっちり練習するの！
Yeah, definitely! Let's go! I've always dreamed of having a sleepover with you all.
行きましょう
ぜひ みんなでお泊まり行くの 夢だったの
Training Camp!